<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Country Profile</string>

    <string name="country1">Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="country2">India</string>
    <string name="country3">Pakistan</string>

    <string name="details1">
        People in many parts of the [western] world still think that Bangladesh is in India and whenever I hear that, I get frustrated and saddened. Bangladesh is considered to be a third world country and the etymology of the term \'third world\' is quite interesting. It was coined by a French economist and demographer named Alfred Sauvy,who considered these developing countries in South Asia, Latin America and Africa to be like the Third Estate in France.
        \n\n
        Bangladesh is one of the poorest and densely populated countries in the world. It is located in South Asia and is bordered by India from three sides, Burma from the southeast corner and the Bay of Bengal from the south. As we studied in our world politics class, political realism which “emphasizes the role of the nation-state and makes a broad assumption that all nation-states are motivated by national interests, or, at best, national interests disguised as moral concerns” comes into play. In 1952, the Language Movement took place, and the purpose was to make Bengali one of the official languages in East Pakistan. They succeeded and in 2000, UNESCO declared 21 February Inernational Mother Language Day to recognize the objective of the Language Movement and promote the ethno-linguistic rights of all citizens. Next, the idea of political realism is highlighted in the 1971 Liberation War in which was fought to gain independence and establish Bangladesh as a sovereign nation.
        \n\n
        The path to achieving democracy in Bangladesh has not been a smooth ride. Starting from 1991, the hot seat, i.e. the prime ministry has been going back and forth in a perpetual cycle between two leaders, Khaleda Zia and Shiekh Hasina. Between 11 January 2007 and 17 December 2008, the most current obstacle to democracy was laid out in the form of an emergency. During this period, the main objective of the caretaker government was to carry out a ‘cleansing process’. In order to combat the plague of corruption, numerous political leaders were arrested on various and diverse charges without going to court since these actions are allowed during an emergency. People welcomed the caretaker government backed by the army with open arms and their actions and decisions were applauded by most members of the upper and middle classes and many members of the lower classes. However, at the end of two years, one must ask, to what extent were the cases followed up in court and also how have these ‘accomplishments’ benefited the political process. The same two leaders who were shamelessly arrested in the second half of 2007 on grounds of corruption ran for the election in December last year, and one was even elected as Prime Minister. Unlike the U.S. and many other countries, an individual is allowed to run for election for more than two terms and it can be argued whether it is high time for Bangladesh to make some changes in its constitution.
        \n\n
        I think that the ‘dependency theory’ which explains a country’s underdevelopment is quite applicable to a country like Bangladesh. As highlighted by our world politics professor, Vincent Ferraro, “dependency theory attempts to explain the present underdeveloped state of many nations in the world by examining the patterns of interactions among nations and by arguing that inequality among nations is an intrinsic part of those interactions.” As mentioned above, Bangladesh’s GDP has risen significantly over the past few years, however, social indicators such as life expectancy, literacy, infant mortality and education paint a bleak picture. One key characteristic of dependent states which is clearly visible is the increased volume of value-added imports. I am truly shocked when I go to the supermarkets and see how much we love the Kellogg cereals and Nestle chocolates. It is true that globalization has benefited countries and has improved the balance of payments considerably, but it is also one of the top reasons which developing countries still rely on the dominant countries and hence remain underdeveloped. Another factor to consider is the extraction of the resources by the multinational organizations which causes the poor countries to remain poor. The idea behind the dependency theory also fits in at the national level. Cities full of resources and opportunities also known as metropoles draw in people from the less developed regions called satellites causing them to rot further. This is one of the main reasons why there is so much inequality in Bangladesh. Income distribution between the upper and lower members of the society is so uneven that when one visits some parts of Dhaka, they will not believe that they are in one the poorest countries in the world.
        \n\n
        The poverty, hunger and backwardness of Bangladesh is often published in the newspapers however it is also important to recognize the socio-economic development that has taken place in the last fifteen years. Bangladesh’s Garments and Textile Industry play a dominant role in poverty alleviation and socio-economic transformation. The Ready-Made Garments (RMG) sector is the biggest earner of foreign currency and one of the largest contributors to GDP. The Pharmaceutical Industry in Bangladesh is significantly picking up the pace and competing in the global markets among emerging giants including China and India. Bangladesh has one of the lowest records of consumption of drugs per capita in the world, which in the past has been caused by the lack in affordability of drugs by the general public and improper healthcare. However, the industry has been a key contributor to the Bangladesh economy amongst other robust sectors such as the RMG. In recent years, the ICT sector has also flourished; cellular phones have flooded the country and internet is also available almost nationwide in telephones as well as computers using more efficient mediums such as fiber optics. This easy flow of information is likely to disseminate knowledge and bring a new meaning to learning and living in a developing country such as Bangladesh.
    </string>

    <string name="details2">
        What is India and what is her identity? Is she as elusive to find as the insides of a seed? A mere country cannot assume the bewitching charms that hang on her slender wrists. So, how to encounter the real India?
        \n\n
        Sit by the ruins, and see the inscriptions carved on the walls of caves, and listen. Listen to the seers and the folklorists, to the waters of the perennial rivers and the echoes from the immortal gigantic mountains. Look at the personifications of prayer carved out of marble or stone, and lie under a banyan tree, and listen - Listen to India.
        \n\n
        India is the name given to the vast peninsula which the continent of Asia throws out to the south of the magnificent mountain ranges that stretch in a sword like curve across the southern border of Tibet. Shaped like an irregular quadrilateral, this large expanse of territory we call India, deserves the name of a subcontinent. Ancient Geographers referred to India as being "constituted with a four-fold conformation" (chatuh samasthana samsthitam), "on its South and West and East is the Great Ocean, the Himavat range stretches along its north like the string of a bow".
        \n\n
        The name Himavat in the above passage refers not only to the snow-capped ranges of the Himalayas but also to their less elevated offshoots - the Patkai, Lushai and Chittagong Hills in the east, and the Sulaiman and Kirthar ranges in the west. These go down to the Sea and separate India from the wooded valley of Irrawady, on the one hand, and the hilly tableland of Iran, on the other. The Himalayas standing tall in breathtaking splendour are radiant in myth and mystery. These, the youngest and tallest mountain ranges, feed the Ganga with never-ending streams of snow. The Himalayas are home to the people of Kashmir, Himachal Pradesh, Uttaranchal, Sikkim and Arunachal Pradesh.
    </string>

    <string name="details3">
        The region of Pakistan was one of the cradles of civilisation. Stone-age hunter-gatherers lived on the Potohar plateau and in the Soan Valley in northern Punjab 300,000 or more years ago. Excavations on the Balochistan plateau show a more advanced culture which flourished from 4000 to 2000 BCE. At Kot Diji in the Khairpur district, an early bronze age culture developed in this period. These early civilisations reached their peak in the Indus valley cities, of which Harappa is the most notable. These societies had mastered town planning and pictographic writing.
        \n\n
        In 327 BCE Alexander the Great invaded with his Macedonian army. Later, Mauryans from India ruled the northern Punjab area, to be replaced by Bactrian Greeks from Afghanistan and central Asian tribes. Different religions prevailed in turn: Buddhism (under the Mauryans), Hinduism and, with Arab conquest in the eighth century, Islam.
        \n\n
        Two main principalities emerged under Arab rule, that of al- Mansurah and that of Multan. The Ghaznarid sultans gained ascendancy in Punjab in the 11th century. The subsequent ascendancy of the Moghuls, who originated in Central Asia, lasted from 1536 to 1707; their rule lingered nominally until 1857. They established a sophisticated imperial administration and left a rich legacy of forts and walled cities, gardens and gateways, mosques and tombs.
        \n\n
        In the early 17th century European traders arrived on the subcontinent. Through the East India Company, the British became the dominant force. After the unsuccessful uprising against Britain of 1857, the British took direct control. Slowly a national Muslim identity emerged, championed by Sir Syed Ahmed Khan (1817–89). The All India Muslim League was founded in 1907.
        \n\n
        As the subcontinent moved towards independence, it became clear that Hindu and Muslim interests could not be reconciled. The campaign to establish an independent Muslim state came to prominence in the 1920s and 30s. It was led by the philosopher and poet Mohammad Iqbal and Mohammad Ali Jinnah.
        \n\n
        Pakistan was created, as an Islamic state, out of the partition of the UK’s Indian Empire, at independence in August 1947. It originally consisted of two parts, West Pakistan (now Pakistan) and East Pakistan (now Bangladesh), separated by 1,600 km of Indian territory. Partition was followed by war with India over Kashmir and the mass migration of Muslims, Hindus and Sikhs to resettle within the new borders, an upheaval which led to violence, financial loss and death on a large scale. With the arrival of Indian Muslims and departure of Pakistan’s Hindus and Sikhs, Pakistan became an almost entirely Muslim society. Jinnah, who is honoured as the Quaid-i-Azam, or great leader, died in 1948.
        \n\n
        In 1956, Pakistan became a federal republic. It has been under military rule for long periods. Its first Prime Minister, Liaquat Ali Khan, was assassinated in 1951. In 1958, martial law was declared and political parties abolished. General (later Field Marshal) Ayub Khan became President in 1960 and allowed a form of guided ‘basic democracy’. However, failure to win the 1965 war against India and accusations of nepotism and corruption undermined his position. In the east, the Awami League of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman voiced the grievances of the Bengali population. Ayub Khan resigned in 1969 and power was taken over by General Yahya Khan, who in December 1970 held the first national elections in independent Pakistan.
        \n\n
        Mujib and the Awami League won an electoral majority in Pakistan’s general election on a platform demanding greater autonomy for East Pakistan. At the same time Zulfikar Ali Bhutto’s Pakistan People’s Party (PPP) gained a majority in the West. Despite Mujib’s victory, he was prevented by the Pakistan authorities from becoming Prime Minister of the combined state and the Awami League then issued their own plans for a new constitution for an independent state in the East. As a result of the military intervention that ensued, civil war broke out in the eastern region in 1971; the Indian army intervened in support of the Bengalis; Pakistan forces withdrew and Bangladesh became an independent state. In 1972 Pakistan withdrew from the Commonwealth but rejoined in 1989.
    </string>

</resources>
